STEPHEN SCHOOLEY

FRONT END
WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

(226) 341-0898
SCHOOLEY.SA@GMAIL.COM
WWW.STEPHENSCHOOLEY.CA
WWW.GITHUB.COM/SCHOOLEYSA

PROFILE

Utilizing a multitude of techniques and languages, I create contemporary, responsive and accessible web design. I have abundant experience in analyzing the systemic interaction between multiple programs to generate creative solutions, in individually driven projects and as both a collaborator and team manager.

SKILLS

- HTML 5, CSS, SCSS
- Responsive and Accessible Design
- JavaScript/ES6
- Working with RESTful APIs, and Firebase
- React (Hooks and classes)
- Version control & collaboration using Git and GitHub
- Paired programming and team-based development
- Project scope management
- Verbal and Written Communication with Clients and Coworkers
- Attention to technical detail

EDUCATION

WEB DEVEVLOPMENT CERTIFICATE
JUNO COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY | 2021

BACHELOR OF MUSIC

WILFRED LAURIER UNIVERSITY | 2012 - 2016

PROJECTS

FILM RECS

CLICK TO TRY!

Responsive and accessible movie recommendation app.
Uses a RESTful API to recommend a film based on a users chosen parameters. Pair programmed in React, utilizing hooks. Users submitted reviews are saved and displayed using a Firebase realtime database.

BLACK JACK

CLICK TO TRY!

Fully playable game of Black Jack built on RESTful API calls. Dealer logic written in vanilla JavaScript.

EXPERIENCE

ON FLOOR SUPERVISOR

ALIGHT SOLUTIONS | OCT 2017 - SEPT 2019

- Resolved errors and analyzed trends by troubleshooting the interaction of multiple programs both in real time with clients and in broader project contexts
- As floor Supervisor, led projects including repeat caller analysis and client satisfaction tracking
- Effectively resolved escalated client issues from Client Care Representative, as well as providing management, mentorship and feedback about CCR performance

SENIOR TECHNICAL ADVISOR

CONCENTRIX | FEB 2016 - SEPT 2017

- Handled difficult or procedurally sensitive customer, utilizing decisive analysis and implementation skills to solve unique and evolving technical issues
- Minimize impact of emerging issues by interfacing with the clients' engineers to track issues and implement solutions in real time to
- Consistently achieved above company average statistics in customer satisfaction, technical efficiency and all other measured areas